Fathullah Auzan Setyo Laksono

+6282234353650 I fathullah.auzan@gmail.com LinkedIn : fathullah auzan I andanfathullah.github.io

About Me

I am a graduate in Computer Engineering with nearly 3 years of experience in Mobile Development. My passion for technology has also led me to delve into machine learning and the Internet of Things.

I was enrolled in the Apple Developer Academy 2023 cohort, learning to build applications with SwiftUI using various Apple technologies such as Core Data, MapKit, CloudKit, and API integration. Additionally, I am working as a Document Engineer to provide technical documentation for every development process at Telkom Indonesia. Every challenge that I encounter has been an opportunity for growth, strengthening my foundation for success in the ever-evolving field of development. This experience has honed my ability to adapt to change, execute tasks according to expectations and deadlines, and enhance critical thinking skills. With my experiences and skills, I have been trained to tackle various challenges in app development, and I believe that my dedication and creativity will positively impact the world of technology.

Education

Institut Teknologi Sepuluh Nopember Surabaya

(October, 2018 – October, 2022)

GPA: 3.5

Bachelor of Computer Engineering

Focuses on the development of a machine learning program aimed at detecting age, gender, and ethnicity of individuals through the analysis of images and videos. The project involved training on tens of thousands of facial datasets using TensorFlow and various neural network architectures. The success of the project is evident in the program's ability to accurately detect age, gender, and ethnicity with a significant level of precision.

Bangkit Academy 2020

(January, 2021 - September, 2021)

Android Developer

Bangkit is a career readiness program that aims to produce high-caliber technical talent for world-class Indonesian technology companies and startups, fully supported by Google, GoTo, and Traveloka.

Working Experiences

IOS Engineer Intern, Apple Developer Academy @ UC

(January, 2023 – Desember, 2023)

- Collaborated with a cross-functional team, including designers and a project manager, I managed to deliver a fully working
 application with different requirements using the Scrum framework and an agile mindset.
- Successfully develop four different app with SwiftUI using apple technology such as MapKit, Core Data, Core ML and CloudKit.
 - SizeAppa: An application designed to assist users in easily recording their body measurements. With an intuitive interface, users can accurately and efficiently store various body measurements. Using Core Data to save user data and preferences. Available on Appstore (https://apps.apple.com/id/app/size-appa/id6473383266)
 - Splivu: Split bill apps with Optical Character Recognition, Bill Management, and Bill Collaboration with unique code. Using CoreML and AVFoundation to seamlessly scan bills and split it according to user preference and CloudKit to save all bill data. Available on Appstore (https://apps.apple.com/id/app/splivu/id6463192326)
 - **Instanery**: Traveling app that generates instant itineraries based on user-preferred destinations, sorted by distance. Using MapKit to display map and routing user destination and alamofire to integrate with API.
 - Mushmate: IoT and apps for maintaining top-quality mushrooms with stable temperature and humidity. I responsible to create the IoT device to control temperature and humidity using ESP32 as its main processor.
 Available on Appstore (https://apps.apple.com/id/app/mushmate-modern-mushroom-farm/id6468881469)

Documentation Engineer, Telkom Indonesia

(September, 2022 – Present)

- Facilitating the development process by providing technical requirement documents such as API contracts, sequence diagrams, and flowmaps using sequencediagram.org, draw,io, postman and notion
- Successfully leading integrations and enhancing user traffic for the application through collaboration with third-party entities.
- Improving developer performance and product team efficiency through the implementation of effective and easily comprehensible document formats.

Documentation Engineer Intern, Telkom Indonesia

(September, 2021 – September, 2022)

• Increase user understanding of application by providing an easy to understand and precise guide book using Figma, Microsoft World and Seguencediagram.org.

Frontend Intern, PT. Andromedia

(February, 2022 – July, 2022)

• Accelerating bug and error resolution by creating a reporting dashboard for users to submit application issues. Using Laravel framework, I create the reporting and chart that count all report via dashboard.

Project Manager, Alpha Collective ID

(March, 2019 - May, 2020)

• Successfully managed and scheduled four branding and documentation projects by providing timelines and budget planning. Additionally, sourced and onboarded talent to execute the projects.

Organization Experiences

Vice Chair of Communication and Information, Himatekkom ITS

(January, 2020 – February, 2021)

- Ensuring the smooth operation of the division by providing bonding activities for members within the division.
- Facilitating the dissemination of information by providing posting templates for important announcements within the organization.

Vice Chairperson, CLICK ITS (Film & Short Movie Enthusiast)

(February, 2019 – January, 2020)

• Ensuring every member in the organization feels comfortable and adapts well to tasks by organizing regular meetings and watching events together.

Additional Information

Skills:

- Programing : SwiftUI, Kotlin, Flutter, Laravel
- Project Manager : Jira, Sprint, Scrum
- Software Testing : Selenium, Apium
- General Documentation: Notion, Postman, Draw.io, Microsoft Word, Microsoft Power Point
- Editing: Figma, Photoshop, Ilustrator, Premiere, After Effect
- Language: Indonesian, English
- Soft Skill: Public Speaking, Collaboration, Team Communication

Certification:

(October 2021)
(April 2021)
(March 2021)
(February 2021)
(January 2021)
(Januari 2024)